Mehmet Yağcı

mehmetyagci53@gmail.com, 90 (555) 336 58 02, İstanbul - Uskudar - Acibadem

Date of Birth : 14.02.1982
Military Status : Completed
Marital Status : Married

Web : yagcimehmet.com

LinkedIn : linkedin.com/in/mehmetyagci

Summary

More than 12 years of hand on experience in software engineering. Awareness and adoption of best practices, object oriented architectures and design patterns. Development of highly reusable, maintainable and sustainable systems. Capability of utilizing issue tracking, source control and package management systems. Domain knowledge in various fields. Excellent command of English especially in technical terms. Supportive and enthusiastic team player dedicated to streamlining processes and efficiently resolving project issues.

Education

Master's Degree İstanbul University Computer Engineering 2014- ... (In thesis stage)

Bachelor's Degree Yıldız Technical University Mathematical Engineering 2000-2006

Foreign Language English (Professional working competence)

Job Experience

Software Engineer Koc Sistem 07.2017-...

Koç Sistem, which is one of Turkey's largest technology companies, working as a backend developer in different projects.

The activities carried out in this context

- Software Engineer
- Bug Fixing
- Performance Improvements
- Software Support

Some of the technologies from used by me::

- Asp.Net Boilerplate Framework.
- Code First for modeling
- Creating WCF services for integrations
- Developing custom Asp.Net MVC 5 application for logging

Software Engineer Yeni Medya Electronic Publishing 11.2016-06.2017 antoloji.com, which is one of the most comprehensive content sharing portals in Turkey, moved its infrastructure to Asp.Net MVC platform.

The activities carried out in this context

- Software Engineer
- Software Deployment
- Software Support
- Software planning, development, testing and deployment without interruption

Development of antoloji.com from scratch with:

- Multitier architecture, Object Oriented Modeling.
- NInject for separation of concerns between tiers
- -.LINQ To SQL for database operations



- PostSharp for database caching
- CDN for server caching
- NUnit for testing

Software Engineer / Project Manager

Fatih Uni. Sema Hospital

11.2008-07.2016

Main integrated hospital information system project took nearly 7 years. (2 year project manager and 5 year product development on sites and continuous development)

Project deployed in 3 domestic and 1 abroad site. In Kazakhstan project used Turkish and Russian at the same time. Lots of side projects and boutique solutions developed during project.

Over 10 integrations on main project with different levels of association developed.

Whole project developed with .NET technologies. We use self-developed ORM at base. Main project was C# Winform. For integration purposes we use and develop lots of web service (XML,REST) solutions.

We also have modules developed in ASP.NET MVC.

Roles throughout the project

- Software Requirements Analysis
- Software Development
- Software Deployment
- Software Project Management

Software Developer

Venero Information Technologies

08.2006-11.2007

Software developed for cargo sector using .NET technologies

Responsibilities

- Design and coding of new modules
- Creation of desired reports

Other Information

Computer Skills

ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET, C#
SQL Server, Oracle
T-SQL
HTML5, CSS,
JavaScript, jQuery,Ajax
Entity Framework, NInject, OOP, AOP, PostSharp
Restful Api WCF, Web Services (JSON, XML)
TFS, Git, Tortoise SVN,
Matlab, Weka
Visual Studio, Sql Management Studio, Jira

Seminars and Couses

Agile and Scrum Trainig	Acm	2018
Saglik-NET Integration Training	Ministry of Health	2016
Advanced Windows Programming with .Net	BT Akademi	2006
Developing Database App. with VB.Net	C and System Prog. Found.	2005
Object Oriented Programming with VB.Net	C and System Prog. Found.	2005

Hobbies

Arduino, Wordpress